Thousands of years ago, there was a series of bizarre occurrences that many believe to have
been the Ten Biblical Plagues. No one thought they could happen again. Until now.
The Reaping is a horror film directed by Stephen Hopkins.
Katherine Morrissey, a former Christian missionary, lost her
faith after the tragic deaths of her family.
Now she applies her expertise to debunking religious phenomena.
When a series of biblical plagues overrun a small town, Katherine arrives to prove that a supernatural force
is not behind the occurrences, but soon finds that science cannot explain what is happening.
Instead, she must regain her faith to combat the
evil that waits in a Louisiana swamp.
Katherine, played by Hilary Swank.
Doug, played by David Morrissey.
Ben, played by Idris Elba.
Loren McConnell, played by AnnaSophia Robb.
Father Costigan, played by Stephen Rea.
Sheriff Cade, played by William Ragsdale.
The Reaping is a 2007 American supernatural horror
thriller film, starring Hilary Swank.
The film was directed by Stephen Hopkins for Warner Bros.
Pictures, Village Roadshow Pictures and Dark Castle Entertainment.
The music for the film was scored by John Frizzell.
The film explores themes of small town, faith, christianity, missionary, river.
The tone is dark.